Paul Huisman

Senior Full Stack Web Developer that has been developing since 2008. Loves to successfully translate the wishes of the client into a beautiful and innovative human-centered software product.

Started out as a frontend developer but moved to backend to find more challenging projects. About three years ago regained a lot of interest in frontend projects because of the interesting and challenging new javascript frameworks like React and VueJs. Since then I consider myself a proper full stack developer. I love sparring with UX/UI to create the best possible experience for the user.

Has a lot of experience working for big clients (FrieslandCampina, Walibi, etc) in scrum teams with other talented creatives. Can stay cool under pressure and handle (realistic) deadlines.

EXPERIENCE

Paul Huisman Development, Rotterdam — Freelance Senior Web Developer

NOVEMBER 2018 - NOW

After 10 years working for agencies I can honestly say I'm experienced enough to start out on my own. I want to build beautiful, smooth, intuitive and innovative web solutions with a human-centered approach.

Dept, Rotterdam — Senior Web Developer

JULY 2017 - OCTOBER 2018

Working on a variety of PHP projects as a senior developer, ranging from Laravel to WordPress.

Hoppinger, Rotterdam — Lead Developer

MAY 2014 - JUNE 2017

As a lead developer I was responsible for the final technical product. Leading the developers in my team and working closely together with the internal project manager and the product owner (client) to get the best result possible.

Hoppinger, Rotterdam — Web Developer

IUNE 2011 - APRIL 2014

Starting off as a young web developer after my graduation, first as a front-end developer, later focusing on backend.

Campagne, Rotterdam — Front-end Web Developer

JUNE 2009 - MAY 2010

Part-time working as a front-end developer during my studies.

+31616379202

paul@paulhuisman.com www.paulhuisman.com

SKILLS

PHP

Laravel

Symfony

Node.js

VueJS

React

Typescript

TailwindCSS, PostCSS

Linux

WordPress

Drupal

Shopify

Ruby on Rails

Test-driven development

Lead development

Scrum

Git

RESTful API design

PROJECTS

Sprinklr.co - Freelance Web Developer

JUNE 2020 - NOW | www.sprinklr.co

Implementing new custom-made solutions for the existing Sprinklr Shopify webshop. Building a customer-login environment with recent ordering info, a custom date delivery tool and more using Javascript (ES6) and Liquid.

Zoncoalitie— Freelance Web Developer

MAY 2020 - AUG 2020 | internal platform

Zoncoalitie is the independent platform for advice and development of solar power projects on commercial and social real estate. Developing the full-scale application as a full-stack developer using Laravel and VueJS.

Stager — Freelance Web Developer

DEC 2019 - APR 2020 | www.stager.nl

Implementing a full redesign for Stager's event management web application using React and Typescript. <u>Stager</u> is Rotterdam-based and offers a one stop shop for planning, promoting and selling events; from single performance to festival, from show to club night.

AUrate New York — Freelance Web Developer

AUG 2019 - APR 2020 | www.auratenewyork.com

Continuous full stack development for <u>AUrate</u>, a New York-based jewelry store. Developing custom dashboards to share insights in all open production processes, barcode scanner apps and advanced webshop filtering middleware using Laravel and VueJS.

Future Proof Retail — Freelance Web Developer

MAY 2019 - AUG 2019

Building a Laravel application for Future Proof Retail which will inspire retail business-owners to deal with the drastic changes in retail through innovation stories and product services.

CMD The Hague — Freelance Web Developer

NOVEMBER 2018 - FEBRUARY 2019 | www.cmd-denhaag.nl

Building a new WordPress website (both back-end and front-end development) for CMD The Hague.

EMPLOYABLE AS

Senior PHP Developer Laravel Developer Node.js Developer VueJS Developer Full Stack Developer Frontend Developer

LANGUAGES

Dutch (native)
English (professional)

Walibi Ticketing API — Senior PHP Developer at Dept Agency

JANUARY 2018 - APRIL 2018 | www.walibi.nl/tickets

Connecting the frontend ticketing sales to a deprecated system which couldn't be cutout in a freshly build RESTful Laravel API. Guiding the entire ticket

ordering flow through numerous routes, validations and services. Building in several queues and caching mechanisms to handle the load (at peak moments 400+ concurrent users).

Ecofont — Senior PHP Developer at Dept Agency

DECEMBER 2017 - JANUARY 2018 | www.ecofont.com

Drupal 8 e-commerce website that contains a custom written module to connect the sales to Mollie and Salesforce.

Sound & Vision Institute — *Senior PHP Developer at Dept Agency*

OCTOBER 2017 - DECEMBER 2017 | www.beeldengeluid.nl

New Drupal 8 portal site for Beeld & Geluid – The Netherlands Institute for Sound and Vision is the institute for media culture; an inspiring, creative and accessible meeting place for both private individuals and professionals.

KoersVO Schoolprofielen — Lead Developer at Hoppinger

JANUARY 2016 | (internal application - no url available)

Symfony2 application that connects all middle-schools in the region Zuid-Holland to prospect students / parents looking for options.

FrieslandCampina — Lead Developer at Hoppinger

JUNE 2016 | www.frieslandcampina.com

Building the corporate website for FrieslandCampina as a multisite platform with WordPress.

Deltares KennisOnline — Lead Developer at Hoppinger

OCTOBER 2016 | www.deltares.nl/nl/publicaties

Building a Rails application combined with ElasticSearch to continuously import and update thousands of articles from a knowledge network database to the corporate Deltares website.

EDUCATION

Hogeschool Rotterdam — Bachelor of Information and Communication Technology

SEPTEMBER 2005 - JUNE 2010